<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jesus Aguado</title>
    <link>https://jesusaguado.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jesus Aguado</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 10:22:10 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jesusaguado.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Decision Trees</title>
      <link>https://jesusaguado.github.io/posts/decision-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 10:22:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jesusaguado.github.io/posts/decision-tree/</guid>
      <description>This post will introduce decision tree classifiers. You can follow along together with the actual implementation in python with the scikit-learn package.
You can follow the code here or download it in Jupyter notebook format together with the dataset in this zipped file.
1. What are decision trees? A decision tree is a statistical or machine learning model geared towards classification or regression. We will focus in the classification problem, and thus we will assume that we have a dataset registering the values of $N$ attributes $(x_1,\dots,x_N)$ and a target variable $y$ which is categorical, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sphere Geometry</title>
      <link>https://jesusaguado.github.io/posts/sphere-geometry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 01:03:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jesusaguado.github.io/posts/sphere-geometry/</guid>
      <description>Geometry and analysis of spatial data on the Earth This is a short post about the DBSCAN algorithm when applied to spatial datapoints on the Earth. I became interested in this when trying to cluster weatherstations in Canada.
Clustering is a technique in unsupervised machine learning that, given a numeric dataset, aims at bundling together some observations based on coordinate similarities. When working with abstract data, we often think of this dataset as lying on \(m\)-dimensional space \(\mathbb{R}^m\), where \(m\) is the number of variables or columns in our data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo</title>
      <link>https://jesusaguado.github.io/posts/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 23:18:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jesusaguado.github.io/posts/hugo/</guid>
      <description>I have started using Hugo for generating the content on this site. It is very lightweight and perfectly suits my needs, as I will be using this site to post regularly.
Hugo has nice features such as handling tags, which permits easy navigation across the site. I am still tinkering with the settings, so expect a few changes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
